Abdullah Itangishaka

WEB DEVELOPER

abdullahitangishaka@gmail.com +1 437-345-9921 linkedin.com/in/itangishaka/ github.com/itangishaka1 itangishaka.com/

PROFILE

Enthusiastic Junior Full Stack Web Developer transitioning from a career working in Business, Electrical, Electronics and Telecommunication to an industry where I can pursue my passion for Web technologies.

My work experience has allowed me to discover my passion for solving problems and helping people. That passion, coupled with an affinity for technology, have led me to software engineering. I have worked hard to acquire the necessary skills to prove that I can be an asset to any technology team.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, React,Redux, Express, MySQL, Agile Development, Document Object Model(DOM) APIs, Web APIs, User Authentication, OAuth, Heroku, GitHub

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma Graduate, Web Development

MAY 2022 - AUG 2022, ONTARIO, CANADA

University of The People | Bachelors in Computer Science SEP 2017 - AUG 2018, ONLINE Passadena, CA 91101, USA

EXPERIENCE

Business Process Analyst | spotwork (spotapp.co)

JAN 2022 - MAY 2022, TORONTO, ON

- Assisted and supported the design and development of required interface and enhancements of the company.
- Analyzed, developed and configured business processes.
- Ensured the project was completed on time and within the budgetary limits
- Successfully created the about page of the company with beautiful animations in only 2 days

Self-Employed | Electrician

JAN 2012 - 2015, KIGALI, RWANDA

- Consulted with clients to determine the scope of projects and make sure that they understand every detail and helped them to understand what the total cost will be.
- Successfully completed wiring and installation of residences and managed a team of 8 assistant laborers, ensured work was correctly done in accordance with safe workplace practices and that suitable tools and equipment were carefully maintained.

STAR Africa Media | Technician

JAN 2009 - 2012, KIGALI, RWANDA

- Attended 6 customers house calls daily that required me to configure decoders, install antennas and repair faulty equipment
- Provided consistently polite and efficient customer service

PROJECTS

Web Developer | Google x BrainStation

JULY 2022 - 24 HOURS HACKATHON

 Collaborated with a team of data scientists and UX designers to develop a Google application to improve the quality of life for people choosing to age in place by centralizing health data and streamlining patient/physician communication.

Capstone Project | Relax Admin

August 2022

- Developed Relax admin full stack app.
- The end users for the Relax Admin System are divided as Students, Staff and the Administrator.
- At the moment: ADMIN is able to:
- Create an account/ do registration Login in the system using the correct credentials; add staff/student/; view staff/student; edit staff/student; delete staff/student https://relax-admin.itangishaka.com/